Silence is not enough.
A Quiet Place Part II is a science fiction, thriller,
horror film directed by John Krasinski.
Following the events at home, the Abbott family now
face the terrors of the outside world.
Forced to venture into the unknown, they realize that the creatures that hunt by
sound are not the only threats that lurk beyond the sand path.
Evelyn Abbott, played by Emily Blunt.
Lee Abbott, played by John Krasinski.
Regan Abbott, played by Millicent Simmonds.
Marcus Abbott, played by Noah Jupe.
Emmett, played by Cillian Murphy.
Man on Island, played by Djimon Hounsou.
A Quiet Place Part II is a 2020 American post-apocalyptic horror film
written, directed, and co-produced by John Krasinski.
It is the sequel to the 2018 film A Quiet Place, following the family from the first film as they continue to
navigate and survive in a post-apocalyptic world inhabited by blind aliens with an acute sense of hearing.
Emily Blunt, Millicent Simmonds, Noah Jupe, and Krasinski reprise their roles from
the first film, while Cillian Murphy and Djimon Hounsou join the cast.
Paramount Pictures began the development of a sequel in April 2018,
following the box-office success of the first film.
By the following August, Krasinski was working on the screenplay, and in
February 2019, he was confirmed as returning to direct.
Krasinski's starting idea for the film was making Simmonds the lead, as he considered her character the
conduit for the themes from the first film that he wanted to expand on in the sequel.
Production took place in Western New York from June to September 2019.
Krasinski was credited with writing the sequel, based on
characters created by Scott Beck and Bryan Woods.
The sequel was produced on a budget of around $55–61 million,
over three times the original's $17 million.
The film had its world premiere in New York City on March 8, 2020; after over a year of postponements due to
the COVID-19 pandemic, it was theatrically released in the United States on May 28, 2021.
It became available to stream on Paramount+ 45 days after its theatrical debut.
The film set several box office records, including the biggest opening weekend
during the course of the pandemic, and grossed $297.5 million worldwide.
It received positive reviews from critics, who praised the story
and the addition of Murphy's character Emmett.
The film was followed by the spin-off prequel A Quiet Place: Day One (2024).
A fourth and final film is scheduled to be released on July 30, 2027.
The film explores themes of new york city, island,
post-apocalyptic future, radio transmission, alien life-form.
The tone is dark and mind_bending and thought_provoking.